# **Rig Quinney**

## Summary

Humble, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Rig-Quinney/8c44b330ee6419bd

Information Technology Professional and Military Veteran with 15 years of proven ability to be a corporate steward interacting and collaborating with multiple levels of management and diverse cultural audiences.

- Managed risk upon multiple lines to protect assets, property, and equipment valued over \$5M, while meeting the expectations of senior leadership.
- Completed CompTIA A+, Network + Training 1/2017. Seeking a rewarding career in Systems Engineering, Windows System Administration, and Server Administration.

Key Focuses: Desktop Support, IT Infrastructure, LAN/WAN, Networking Protocols, Training and Development, Network/Troubleshooting, Project Management, Organization/Communication.

SECURITY CLEARANCE: Secret Security Clearance (In-active) MILITARY SERVICE United States Army 31R

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## IT Project Manager (Contract)

HEWLETT-PACKARD - Houston, TX - July 2015 to September 2016

Managed 5 personnel that supported information technology (IT) processes for 20+ departments. Directed concurrent projects, including research and development hardware lab support of laptops, tablets and desktops. Consulted groups to improve processes

- Rebuilt a team of 5 to produce quality customer service to customers; restructured pay scale, promoted, hired and dismissed employees. Accountable for all work of my employees; developed daily tracking metrics and ticketing system within SharePoint to monitoring team's daily work.
- Integral to the delivery of cross-functional and departmental troubleshooting of unique systems, software, applications and programs; counted on to deliver recommendations for solutions and improvement.
- Inventory control of all computers, tablets, accessories, and all commodities.

## **Rig IT Support Analyst (Contract)**

SHELL - Houston, TX - August 2014 to July 2015

Provided IT infrastructure and application support to troubleshoot applications and telecommunications using virtual machines in RIAB (Rig in a Box) server and resolve multiple rig site issues.

- IT infrastructure and application support, and with drilling operations and drilling data models. Hands-on trouble shooting of complex issues with IT infrastructure, applications and telecommunications.
- Manage IP scheme across all rigs to ensure proper network management and troubleshooting. Troubleshoot Network issues to include satellite connections, routers, modems, switches to include isolated vlan network.
- Creating, modifying and or removing Active Directory accounts and groups for all Shell TLS personnel.
- Troubleshoot and resolve Radio over IP (ROIP) issues between teams.

### Windows Systems Administrator

SHIPCOM WIRELESS - Houston, TX - October 2013 to August 2014

Maintained Real Time Location System (RTLS) of RFID over Wi-Fi active and passive tags for Supply Chain Management System in Veterans Administration facilities and supported Catamaran XCare applications Supply Chain Management software. Installed and troubleshot printers and Barcode scanners.

- \* Responsible for RTLS (Real Time Location System) of RFID over WIFI both Active and Passive Tags for Supply Chain Management System in VA Facilities.
- \* Rackspace Administrator create, change, and delete user accounts per request to include cellular devices. Exposure to Active Directory. Carbonite Backup Administrator. Helpdesk Support internal and external customers with support via phone email and remote desktop support.
- \* System Administrator duties. Install Computrace on Computers.
- \* Ensures that system hardware, operating systems, software systems, and related procedures adhere to organizational values, enabling staff, and customers.

## **Software Support Analyst**

CANRIG DRILLING TECHNOLOGIES - Houston, TX - October 2011 to March 2013

Supported multiple oil rig instrumentation software using Citrix Radmin viewer and Adobe Web Connect. Conducted WITS setup and troubleshooting, satellite connection restores, IP verification and configuration on host computers. Troubleshot networking issues including satellite connections, printers, routers, modems and switches.

- Troubleshoot and resolve day to day software and hardware issues for Canrig/Nabors Customers. Manage IP scheme across all rigs to ensure proper network management and troubleshooting. Troubleshoot Network issues to include satellite connections, network printers, routers, modems, switches.
- Verify the correct IP addresses are properly configured on host computers to allow connectivity to Citrix using various commands via command line interface to include pinging and trace route methods.
- Troubleshoot other wireless connections on the rig to restore connections. Repair issues dealing with the SQL Databases in regards to the Rig watch Software which is Linux based using multiple different scripts.
- Unlock accounts and passwords to my wells so that users can view and analyze data collected from the various oil rigs
- Create tickets using the JIRA ticketing system. Tested software in Lab environment to simulate issues that can't be done in real time.

## **Technical Support Analyst**

TEXAS SOUTHERN UNIVERSITY - Houston, TX - April 2010 to October 2011

Supported 9 department in The College of Science and Technology in troubleshooting network, hardware and software installation and applications, and providing specialized end-user support to diagnose and resolve local problems related to domain, server and work order system administration.

- Troubleshoot problems with network, hardware and software installation and application. Provide specialized user support services to diagnose and resolve problems. Support domain, server, and work order system administration.
- Installed, maintained, configured, tracked and repaired desktop computer equipment, components, and peripherals. Assisted in the assessment of user training needs.
- Trained and assisted end users in proper use of equipment and software applications related to department services and activities. Maintained inventory of all lab equipment and electronic components used by students for general lab experiments. Consulted with Vendors to Rebuild and Replace Broken Equipment.
- Coordinated with OIT to resolve viruses and problems associated with the server, e-mail, and other technology components. Served as technical resource to the division or department in determining computing needs, strategies, and equipment. Performs other job-related duties as assigned. Installed software AVEVA, Auto Cad,

Solid Edge ST, Unigraphics NX, Symantec Antivirus, Multisim, patches, updates and maintaining computer workstations; Experience troubleshooting basic network, software and printing problems on computer workstations.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science

Information Systems Management Keller Graduate School - Houston, TX

#### **Bachelor of Science**

Technical Management Devry University - Houston, TX

#### **SKILLS**

SKILLS • Technical Skills Mac/Microsoft Windows (95, 98, XP, Vista), Windows 7, 8 & 10, Linux, Red Hat Fedora, Android, IOS • Protocols: Microsoft applications, Operating Systems, Topologies, Infrastructure, Windows Systems Support NTFS Permissions, Malware and Virus Removal Upgrades, Network Troubleshooting, Addressing Technical Problems, • Software: Microsoft Office (2003, 2007, 2010, 2013) Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OneNote, Outlook, Office 365, Visio, SharePoint, Adobe Web Connect, Team Viewer, Rackspace, Jira Ticketing System, Solar winds Ticketing system, Remedy • Hardware: Desktops, Laptops, Tablets Cellular Devices GSM,CDMA, Servers, Administration, Virtualization Knowledge o Network Technologies: LAN/WAN, Ethernet, Networking P2P, Fiber Optics, DHCP, TCP/IP, FTP, DNS, Wireless Technologies. Cloud Computing Knowledge, (laaS) Rackspace, (SaaS) Office 365, Remote Support Soft Skills Successfully managed a team hired and dismissed employees. Tracked team progress using the metrics system. Excellent Customer service skills to all types of personalities. Excellent Troubleshooting Skills in the technology field (10+ years)

#### **LINKS**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rig-quinney-iii-b8aa2513

## MILITARY SERVICE

Service Country: US Branch: U.S. Army

Rank: E4

May 1997 to May 2001

Installs, operates, and performs unit level maintenance on multichannel line-of-site and tropospheric scatter communications systems, antennas and associated equipment. Analyzes BIT/BITE diagnostics to isolate faults to the Line Replaceable Unit (LRU). Installs, operates, performs strapping, restrapping, PMCS, and unit level maintenance on COMSEC devices. Operates and performs Preventive Maintenance Checks and Services (PMCS) on assigned vehicles. Installs, operates, and performs PMCS on assigned power generators.

#### CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

CERTIFICATIONS •CompTIA Network+ Certification (In Progress) •Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA: Server 2012) olnstalling & Configuring Windows Server 2012 Certification (In Progress) oAdministering Windows Server 2012 Certification (In Progress) oConfiguring Advanced Windows Server Services Certification (In Progress)

•Certified Cisco Network Associate (CCNA) olnterconnected Cisco Networking Devices 1 (ICND1) Certification (In Progress) olnterconnected Cisco Networking Devices 2 (ICND2) Certification (In Progress)